# )mitrii **Maksimov**

Erlangen, Germany

📕+49 15203762106 | 💌 maksimov.dmitry.m@gmail.com | 🖸 Maksimov-Dmitry | 🛅 Maksimov-Dmitry | 💆 maksimov.dmitry.m | 💃 dmitrymaksimov

# Summary.

3+ years of diverse data science experience with specialties in market research, data visualization, market optimization and model lifecycle. 2+ years of diverse data/software engineering experience with specialties in pipelines integration, architecure design using AWS, database maintenance and deployment.

1+ years of diverse machine learning engineering with a focus on model management and deployment.

In addition, while studying at the university and various courses(e.g. MADE from VK), I learned many skills like: NLP, LLM, Reinforcement Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Pytorch, Transformers, Huggingface, PyTorch Lightning, Optimization, Spark, Hadoop, Scala, Recommender Systems, kubernetes, algorithms, A/B testing and data structures.

Love to share knowledge with different communities. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for various tasks and learning new technologies and tools.

## Skills\_

AWS, Docker, GitHub, Retool, Linux, Bash, REST API, Google Cloud, CI/CD, MLflow, AimStack, Hydra, Vertex AI

Statistical Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Probability Theory, XGBoost, PyTorch, scikit-learn, ETL, Vertica, Search Engine **ML/Data Science** 

Optimization, PostgreSQL, Market Research, Parsing, Streamlit

**Programming** Python, SQL, SAS base Languages Russian, English, German

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**GFK** Nuremberg, Germany

DATA SCIENTIST/MLOPS & WORK STUDY

Apr. 2022 - Oct. 2023

- Developing a method to detect AoI (areas of interests)
- · Investigating cannibalisation effects
- Evaluating competitors algorithm
- Maintained the CI/CD pipeline
- Migrated a Deep Learning model to Vertex AI on Google Cloud
- Stack: Python, Google Cloud Platform, Streamlit, PostgreSQL, Vertex AI, CI/CD

· Creating a tool to compare segmentations and their impact on the market

T.C.R. International

DATA/SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sep. 2020 - Apr 2022

- · Developed and maintained processes for financial systems, with 90% of the processes developed with my active participation
- Optimized airflow dags and configuration which allowed reducing the cost of the astronomer by 70%
- · Investigated strategies and solutions to reduce AWS infrastructure costs, optimizing resource allocation and usage
- Maintained the infrastructure, specifically working with AWS S3 and RDS
- Developed several AWS Lambda functions for automation and streamlined processing
- · Created a Deep Learning trading algorithm to optimize trading strategies and predict market movements
- Implemented processes for maintaining an extensive internal symbology database consisting of over 30,000 symbols
- · Stack: Python, AWS (S3, RDS, Lambda), Airflow, PostgreSQL, Retool, REST API, Docker, CI/CD, PyTorch, XGBoost, AimStack, Hydra, Blankly(backtesting)

**SDVOR** Moscow, Russia

DATA SCIENTIST Apr. 2020 - Jan. 2022

- Creating an attribution model in advertising for SDVOR site using Markov chain as a result advertising costs decreased by 5%
- Programming ETL workflows for competitors site's parsing
- · Building service to optimize price for sales using SAS, python, SQL, which increased the profit on some products by 10%
- · Accomplishing computer vision model to compare planorgam and realogram via photo in a shop
- Creating telegram-bot as a server for different tasks
- Stack: Python, SAS, Vertica, PostgreSQL, Telegram API

# Education

#### FAU(Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg)

Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany

M.S. IN DATA SCIENCE Oct. 2021 - Present

Developed Personalized Anomaly Detection Model based on continuous-time LSTM and Bayesian Decision Theory.
 Stack: Pytorch, AimStack/MLFlow, Hydra

#### **BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)**

Moscow, Russia

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2021

· Finished 1 semester

#### BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

Moscow, Russia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

• GPA - 4.42, max - 5.0

# **Extracurricular Activity**

MADE at VK

Moscow, Russia

**STUDENT** Sep. 2022 - Jun. 2023

- · Gained expertise in different areas of ML (e.g. NLP, DL, Computer Vision, MLOps, basic ML, Python, ML in BigData, etc)
- Core member in a project to create a recommendation system for articles' authors
- Core member in a project to create a User Request-Based Fake Web Document Text Generation system

ML at Mail.ru Group

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT

Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

· Gained knowledge in basic ML

# **Certificates**

Aug. 2023 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS

Jun. 2023 MADE Big Data Academy. Machine Learning Engineer, VK

405-67419

Oct. 2022 Completion of the Deep Learning Exercise, FAU

Mar. 2020 Labeled data learning, Coursera

Mar. 2020 Math and Python for data analysis, Coursera

2019 **C/C++**, Mail.ru Group

# **Honors & Awards**

#### INTERNATIONAL AWARDS

Jan. 2023 **8th Place**, Tensor Tournament

Erlangen, Germany

Oct. 2022 2nd Place, Classification of Solar Cell Defects

Erlangen, Germany

### DOMESTIC AWARDS

2021 **1st Place**, SDVOR Hacking Competition

Tyumen, Russia